Savanna Baxter

Email: srosebaxter@gmail.com Cell: 704-634-9865 Address: Mooresville, NC, 28117 Website: srbaxter.github.io LinkedIn: savannabaxter GitHub: srbaxter Twitter: srosebaxter

Summary

Recent honors graduate with a B.S. in Computer Science from North Carolina State University with experience developing web applications and websites. One year of extensive internship and project experience both personally and with a well-known company. Seeking further opportunities to leverage front-end skills in a collaborative environment.

Education

May 2016 **North Carolina State University**

Raleigh, NC

- B.S. in Computer Science, Minor in Music
- 3.667 Cumulative GPA and 3.441 Major GPA

Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, Java, C Technologies: Git, GitHub, AWS, Eclipse/IntelliJ, Jenkins, MS Office Personal: Excellent written and verbal communication, team collaboration Miscellaneous: Music theory and performance, computer music composition

Experience

NC State Senior Design Project, Raleigh, NC

January - May 2016

SAS: Dynamic IT Dashboard

- Transformed a static, hard-coded, network monitoring dashboard into an interactive one hosted in AWS to make network issues more noticeable for support teams
- Used D3.js, JavaScript, and HTML5 to generate donut charts to display and sound alerts

SAS Institute Inc., Cary, NC

May - August 2015

Business Intelligence Research & Development Intern

- Translated an existing JavaScript Dependency Analyzer (JDA) back-end Python tool into a RESTful OpenUI5 web application using Flask and jQuery
- Reduced developer confusion and lookup time regarding class dependencies

Leadership and Honors

Women in Computer Science (WiCS)

Fall 2012 - Spring 2016

President, Ambassador, & Mentor

- Organized rooms, sponsors, and other details to host DiamondHacks
- Officiated officer meetings and 1-2 professional and social events each month
- Served as a Mentor for three younger computer science students

Professional Engineering Sorority - Alpha Omega Epsilon *EOS Committee Co-Chair*

Spring 2013 - 2016

- Acted as Webmaster for three semesters to rebuild our website, Facebook, and Twitter pages Professional Development Committee Co-Chair
 - Held events about Robert's Rules of Order, graduate school, and job interviews

University Scholars Program

Fall 2012 - Spring 2016

Power Sound of the South Marching Band

Fall 2012 - 2015

Women in Science and Engineering (WISE)

Fall 2012 - Spring 2014

Ambassador

- Led five tours of Lee Hall while answering questions about WISE and NC State